If you've been thinking about US politics
在过去一年左右，如果你一直在思考美国的政治
and trying to make sense of it for the last year or so,
并试图理解它,
you might have hit on something like the following three propositions:
你可能会碰到以下三个命题：
one, US partisanship has never been so bad before;
一，美国的党派关系从未如此糟糕；
two,
二，
for the first time, it's geographically spatialized --
首次，这种关系是地理空间化的
we're divided between the coasts, which want to look outwards,
我们分裂为两部分，一边是想要向外看的海岸地区，
and the center of the country, which wants to look inwards;
另一边是想要向内看的内陆；
and third,
第三，
there's nothing we can do about it.
我们对此无能为力。
I'm here to today to say that all three of these propositions,
我今天来这里说所有这三个命题，
all of which sound reasonable,
所有这些听起来虽然很合理，
are not true.
它们是错误的。
In fact,
事实上，
our US partisanship goes all the way back to the very beginning of the republic.
我们美国的党派关系可追溯到到共和国的开始。
It was geographically spatialized in almost eerily the same way that it is today,
在地理上的空间化几乎和今天是同样的，
and it often has been throughout US history.
这种情况贯穿了美国历史。
And last,
最后，
and by far most importantly,
最重要的是，
we actually have an extraordinary mechanism
我们实际上有一个非凡的机制
that's designed to help us manage factional disagreement and partisanship.
旨在帮助我们管理党派分歧和党派关系。
That technology is the Constitution.
这种技术是宪法。
And this is an evolving, subtly, supplely designed entity
这是一个不断变化的，微妙的，设计精良的实体
that has the specific purpose
它的具体目的
of teaching us how to manage factional disagreement where it's possible to do that,
就是去教我们如何尽可能管理好派别分歧，
and giving us techniques for overcoming that disagreement when that's possible.
并给我们技巧方法去尽可能克服这种分歧。
Now, in order to tell you the story,
为了告诉你们这个故事，
I want to go back to a pivotal moment in US history,
我想回到美国历史中的关键时刻，
and that is the moment
那就是
when factional disagreement and partisanship was born.
派别的分歧和多党派诞生的时候。
There actually was a birth moment --
在一个诞生的时刻，
a moment in US history when partisanship snapped into place.
美国的党派关系腾空出现。
The person who's at the core of that story is James Madison.
故事核心人物是詹姆斯·麦迪逊。
And at the moment that this began,
那时，
James Madison was riding high.
詹姆斯·麦迪逊正享受成功。
He himself was the Einstein of not only the US Constitution,
他不仅仅是美国宪法的创建者，
but of constitutional thought more globally,
更是全球宪法思想之父，
and, to give him his due,
公正地来说
he knew it.
他知道。
In a period of time of just three years,
在短短三年的时间里，
from 1785 to 1788,
从1785年到1788年，
he had conceived, theorized, designed, passed and gotten ratified the US Constitution.
他设想，理论化，设计，通过并得到批准美国宪法。
And just to give you some sense of the enormity of what that accomplishment actually was,
让你们认识一下这个成就的巨大规模，
although Madison couldn't have known it at the time,
虽然麦迪逊当时不知道，
today that same constitutional technology that he invented is still in use
如今，他设计的宪法技术仍被使用，
not only in the US,
不仅在美国，
but, 230 years later,
230年后，
in places like Canada,
在加拿大，
India,
印度，
South Africa,
南非，
Brazil.
巴西。
So in an extraordinary range of contexts all over the world,
所以在世界各地，这个非凡的范围中
this technology is still the dominant,
这项技术依然占主导地位，
most used, most effective technology to manage governance.
是最常用，最有效的政府管理技术。
In that moment,
在那一刻，
Madison believed that, having solved this problem,
麦迪逊认为，宪法问题解决了后，
the country would run smoothly,
国家会运行顺利，
and that he had designed a technology that would minimize the results of factions
他设计的宪法技术将使派系斗争的结果最小化，
so there would be no political parties.
所以不会产生多政党。
Remarkably, he thought he had designed a constitution
值得注意的是，他觉得他设计的宪法
that was against political parties
是反对政党化的，
and would make them unnecessary.
会让多党派变得没有必要。
He had gotten an enormous degree of help
他得到了很大的帮助
in the final marketing phase of his constitutional project
在他的宪法项目的最后营销阶段
from a man you may have heard of, called Alexander Hamilton.
从一个你可能听说过的男人，叫亚历山大·汉密尔顿。
Now, Hamilton was everything Madison was not.
汉密尔顿和麦迪逊是相反两极。
He was passionate, where Madison was restrained.
汉密尔顿充满激情，麦迪逊却更加保守。
He was pansexual,
汉密尔顿是泛性恋，
where Madison didn't speak to a woman except for once until he was 42 years old,
而麦迪逊在42岁之前只和一个女人说过话，
and then married Dolley and lived happily ever after for 40 years.
之后，他与多丽结婚40多年来一直幸福生活。
(Laughter)
（笑声）
To put it bluntly,
直言不讳，
Hamilton's the kind of person
汉密尔顿是那种人
about whom you would write a hip-hop musical --
你会为他创作一部嘻哈音乐剧，
(Laughter)
（笑声）
and Madison is the kind of person about whom you would not write a hip-hop musical.
而麦迪逊身上毫无“嘻哈“元素，
(Laughter)
（笑声）
Or indeed, a musical of any kind at all.
你甚至都无法为他创作一部正经的音乐剧。
But together,
但是在一起，
they had become a rather unlikely pairing,
他们成为一个不太可能的配对，
and they had produced the Federalist Papers,
他们共同写了《联邦主义论》，
which offered a justification
它为宪法的营销计划，
and, as I mentioned,
正如我所说，
a marketing plan for the Constitution,
给出了理由。
which had been wildly effective and wildly successful.
这是非常有效的并大获成功。
Once the new government was in place,
新政府到位，
Hamilton became Secretary of the Treasury,
汉密尔顿成为财政部长，
and he had a very specific idea in mind.
他有一个非常具体的想法。
And that was to do for financial institutions and infrastructure
那就是创立金融机构和基础设施
exactly what Madison had done for constitutions.
正如麦迪逊为了宪法所做的一样。
Again, his contemporaries all knew it.
他的同时代人也都知道。
One of them told Madison,
其中一人告诉麦迪逊，
who can't have liked it very much,
他可能不愿意看到
that Hamilton was the Newton of infrastructure.
汉密尔顿作为美国基础设施的创立者。
The idea was pretty straightforward.
这个想法很简单。
Hamilton would give the United States a national bank,
汉密尔顿会为美国创立一个国家银行，
a permanent national debt --
一笔永久国债
he said it would be "immortal," his phrase --
他说那将会是 “永恒不变的”，
and a manufacturing policy that would enable trade and manufacturing rather than agriculture,
并会制定生产政策，这将使贸易和制造业超越农业，
which was where the country's primary wealth had historically been.
成为美国的首要财务来源。
Madison went utterly ballistic.
麦迪逊极力反驳。
And in this pivotal, critical decision,
在这个至关重要的决定中，
instead of just telling the world that his old friend Hamilton was wrong
麦迪逊并没有告诉大家他的老朋友汉密尔顿错了，
and was adopting the wrong policies,
采取了错误的政策，
he actually began to argue
他反而开始争论
that Hamilton's ideas were unconstitutional --
汉密尔顿的想法违反了宪法，
that they violated the very nature of the Constitution that the two of them had drafted together.
违反了他俩一起起草的宪法本质。
Hamilton responded the way you would expect.
汉密尔顿的回答正如我们可以预料得到的。
He declared Madison to be his "personal and political enemy" --
他宣称麦迪逊是他的“个人和政治敌人”
these are his words.
这些是他的原话。
So these two founders who had been such close friends and such close allies and such partners,
两位国父曾经是亲密的朋友、盟友和合作伙伴，
then began to produce enmity.
现在开始产生敌意。
And they did it in the good, old-fashioned way.
他们的做法非常老派。
First, they founded political parties.
首先，他们各建政党。
Madison created a party originally called the Democratic Republican Party --
麦迪逊创造了“民主共和党 ”
"Republican" for short --
简称“共和党”，
and Hamilton created a party called the Federalist Party.
汉密尔顿建立了联邦党。
Those two parties adopted positions on national politics
这两方的政治立场
that were extreme and exaggerated.
非常极端和夸张。
To give you a clear example:
给你一个明确的例子：
Madison, who had always believed
麦迪逊一直相信
that the country would have some manufacturing and some trade and some agriculture,
国家应有一些制造业和一些贸易和一些农业，
began attacking Hamilton
开始攻击汉密尔顿
as a kind of tool of the financial markets
说他是金融市场的工具
whom Hamilton himself intended to put in charge of the country.
一切都是汉密尔顿用来控制整个国家的伎俩。
That was an overstatement,
听起来是很夸张，
but it was something Madison came to believe.
但麦迪逊的确这样想。
He also attacked city life,
他还攻击城市生活方式，
and he said that the coasts were corrupt,
他说，海岸城市是腐败的，
and what people needed to do was to look inwards to the center of the country,
人们需要向内陆看齐回到国家的中心，
to farmers, who were the essence of Republican virtue,
尊重农民，他们是共和党的美德，
and they should go back to the values that had made American great,
人民应该回归使美国伟大的价值观
specifically the values of the Revolution,
特别是革命
and those were the values of low taxes,
和低税收的价值观，
agriculture
增强农业
and less trade.
并减少贸易。
Hamilton responded to this by saying that Madison was naïve,
汉密尔顿回应说麦迪逊太天真的，
that he was childish,
太幼稚，
and that his goal was to turn the United States into a primitive autarchy,
他称麦迪逊的目标会将美国变为一个原始的独裁国家
self-reliant and completely ineffectual on the global scale.
只能自力更生，在全球范围内完全不起作用。
(Laughter)
（笑声）
They both meant it,
他们都是认真的，
and there was some truth to each of their claims,
他们的主张中有些属实，
because each side was grossly exaggerating the views of the other
因为每一方都是极力夸张对方的意见
in order to fight their war.
为了打赢这场战争。
They founded newspapers,
他们各自创立报纸，
and so for the first time in US history,
所以在美国历史上第一次，
the news that people received came entirely through the lens
人们的新闻来源不是来自共和党
of either the Republican or the Federalist party.
就是来自于联邦党。
How does this end?
一切是怎么结束的？
Well, as it turned out, the Constitution did its work.
事实证明，宪法起了作用。
But it did its work in surprising ways
但它起作用的方式令人惊讶，
that Madison himself had not fully anticipated.
麦迪逊自己也没有充分预料到。
First, there was a series of elections.
首先，有一系列的选举。
And the first two times out of the box,
而前两次开箱，
the Federalists destroyed the Republicans.
联邦党摧毁了共和党。
Madison was astonished.
麦迪逊很惊讶
Of course, he blamed the press.
他当然指责新闻界。
(Laughter)
（笑声）
And in a rather innovative view --
他提出了一个十分创新的观点——
Madison never failed to innovate when he thought about anything --
麦迪逊不管发生什么都会提出创新的想法 ——
he said the reason that the press was so pro-Federalist
他说新闻界偏心于联邦党的原因是
is that the advertisers were all Federalists,
广告商都是联邦党人，
because they were traders on the coasts who got their capital from Britain,
因为联邦党徒是海岸线城市的贸易商从大英帝国拿钱
which Federalism was in bed with.
和英国关系混乱不清。
That was his initial explanation.
那是他的初步解释。
But despite the fact that the Federalists, once in power,
但是，联邦党人掌权之后，
actually enacted laws that criminalized criticism of the government --
颁布了法律治罪于那些批评政府的人，
that happened in the United States --
这些在美国都发生过，
nevertheless,
尽管如此，
the Republicans fought back,
共和党人开始反击，
and Madison began to emphasize the freedom of speech,
麦迪逊开始强调言论自由，
which he had built into the Bill of Rights,
他早已把这写入《人权法案》，
and the capacity of civil society to organize.
和允许成立民间组织的自由。
And sure enough, nationally,
当然，在全国，
small local groups -- they were called Democratic-Republican Societies --
被称为“民主共和团”的地方团体
began to form and protest against Federalist-dominated hegemony.
开始联合抗议联邦党强势的霸权。
Eventually, the Republicans managed to win a national election --
最终共和党赢得全国大选，
that was in 1800.
那是在1800年。
Madison became the Secretary of State,
麦迪逊成为国务卿，
his friend and mentor Jefferson became president,
他的朋友和导师杰斐逊成为总统，
and they actually, over time,
而实际上，随着时间的推移，
managed to put the Federalists completely out of business.
他们设法使联邦党完全失去业务。
That was their goal.
这就是他们的目标。
Now, why did that happen?
为什么会这样呢？
It happened because in the structure of the Constitution
这是因为宪法的结构
were several features that actually managed faction
有几个功能可以管理党派分歧，
the way there were supposed to do in the first place.
这本是首先应该做的事。
What were those?
那些是什么？
One -- most important of all -- the freedom of speech.
第一，最重要的一点就是言论自由。
This was an innovative idea at the time.
在当时，这是一个创新的想法。
Namely, that if you were out of power,
也就是说，如果你失去了政权
you could still say that the government was terrible.
你还可以说政府是可怕的
Two,
第二，
civil society organization.
民间社会组织。
The capacity to put together private groups, individuals, political parties and others
组织私人团体，个人，政党等
who would organize to try to bring about fundamental change.
会带来根本的变化。
Perhaps most significantly was the separation of powers --
也许最重要的一条是分权原则，
an extraordinary component of the Constitution.
它是宪法最非凡的部分。
The thing about the separation of powers
分权原则
is that it did then and it does now,
不管是在当时还是现在
drive governance to the center.
将治理推向中心。
You can get elected to office in the United States
在美国，你可以当选，
with help from the periphery,
通过外围的力量
right or left.
不管是左派还是右派。
It turns out,
事实证明，
you actually can't govern unless you bring on board the center.
除非你着重中心，你无法治理。
There are midterm elections that come incredibly fast after a presidency begins.
中期选举会在 总统职位开始没多久后马上举行。
Those drive presidents towards the center.
这些都会促使总统注重中间派。
There's a structure in which the president, in fact, does not rule
其中存在一个结构，其实总统并不统治
or even govern,
也并不能管理，
but can only propose laws which other people have to agree with --
他们只能提案，而这些提案必须经过他人的同意。
another feature that tends to drive presidents
这就是宪法结构的一个特点
who actually want to get things done to the center.
促使总统着力于最中心。
And a glance at the newspapers today will reveal to you
今日的报纸会透露出
that these principles are still completely in operation.
这些原则依然在运行。
No matter how a president gets elected,
无论总统如何当选，
the president cannot get anything done
总统不能做任何事情
unless the president first of all follows the rules of the Constitution,
除非总统首先遵循《宪法》的规定，
because if not,
若是没有遵循，
the courts will stand up, as indeed has sometimes occurred,
法院将采取措施，确实有时会发生，
not only recently, but in the past, in US history.
不仅最近，但在过去，在美国历史上。
And furthermore,
此外，
the president needs people,
总统需要人民，
elected officials who know they need to win election from centrist voters,
民选官员知道他们需要从中间派选民中赢得选举。
also to back his or her policies in order to pass laws.
也要支持他或她的政策以通过法规。
Without it, nothing much happens.
没有它，没什么事情可以发生。
The takeaway of this brief excursus into the history of partisanship, then, is the following:
这个简短的美国党派历史的关键点在于
partisanship is real;
党派是真实的
it's profound;
它是深刻的
it's extraordinarily powerful,
它非常强大，
and it's terribly upsetting.
也会令人十分沮丧。
But the design of the Constitution is greater than partisanship.
但宪法的设计大于党派。
It enables us to manage partisanship when that's possible,
它使我们能够管理党派在可能的时候，
and it enables us actually to overcome partisan division
它实际上使我们能够克服党派分裂
and produce compromise,
并产生妥协，
when and only when that is possible.
只有当可能的时候。
A technology like that is a technology that worked
这样的技术 是一种有效的技术
for the founders,
对于国父来说，
it worked for their grandchildren,
它为他们的孙辈服务
it didn't work at the moment of the Civil War,
它在内战时没有起作用，
but then it started working again.
但后来又开始有用了。
And it worked for our grandparents,
它为我们的祖父母服务，
our parents,
服务我们的父母，
and it's going to work for us.
它也将为我们起效。
(Applause)
（掌声）
So what you should do is really simple.
所以你应该做的很简单。
Stand up for what you believe in,
支持你所相信的，
support the organizations that you care about,
支持你所关注的组织，
speak out on the issues that matter to you,
说出对你很重要的问题，
get involved,
参与其中，
make change,
改变，
express you opinion,
表达你的观点，
and do it with respect and knowledge and confidence
并且用尊重，知识和信心去做，
that it's only by working together
只有人们共同合作，
that the constitutional technology can do the job that it is designed to do.
宪法技术才会发挥它设计好的作用。
Stand up for what you believe,
捍卫你所相信的，
but take a deep breath while you do it.
但是在你做的时候要深吸一口气。
It's going to be OK.
一切都会没有事。
Thanks.
谢谢。
(Applause)
（掌声）